While it's great that we can query our database
through the content provider, it would be nice if
we could also use the content provider to put
data in. We'll begin with the insert function. Let's fill
the insert function with the same URI matcher code
we had in the other content provider functions but with
one change. We're only going to match the base
URIs. There's a good reason for this. When we insert
into our database, we want it to notify every
content observer that might have data modified by our
insert. It turns out that cursors register themselves as
notify for descendents which means that notifying the root
URI. We'll also notify all descendents of that URI.
If we were to notify based on anything else
other than the root URI. Then a cursor listening
on the root URI will not get notified of a
change that would certainly impact it. So we have to
be very careful when doing that. For this reason it makes
a lot of sense to only allow insertions at our
root URI into our database. That way, it's very, very easy
to handle notifications. It means that we also don't have
to build a combination query for our insert. Containing a parameter
coming from the URI. With the rest of the parameters
coming from a function. So for weather we just pass the
parameters into a database insert call. We should
throw an exception if the insert fails. The
only trick here is to make sure we
return the correct value, which is a URI. Fortunately
we made a function to build these URIs
which contain the weather path followed by an
ID. Let's go task this. Once again, we
go to test provider and we modify our test.
Because after all it's supposed to be test insert
read provider. Here's our insert statement. Obviously it's still talking
to the database. We're going to want to make it
talk to the provider. As always, that's pretty straight forward.
We always get our provider by using our content
resolver so we can replace this insert statement with the
db with a content resolver instead. And of course
we don't use a content resolver against a table name.
Instead we do it against the WeatherEntry.content URI.
But there's still something wrong. Of course, we
don't actually return the weather row ID, we
return the URI. But we can still get a
weather row ID. How do we do that?
Quite simply. Using a helper function in content
URI's, and we don't really need that insert.
After all, we know that this content resolver function
isn't actually going to return unless the value is true. Now that we
finished that, let's run the test. And make sure that we can actually
insert using our content provider. And our test passed. Well, you know what
time it is. Time for you to write some of this as well.